Katrina Butler

1401 Prince of Wales Dr. Apt# 203, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, K2C 3J8 613-297-7290

kat.a.butler@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Software Developer with professional experience in front-end development, enthusiastic about new technologies, and am always excited to start new projects. I am an innovative individual with excellent communication and interpersonal skills. If I'm not engaged in my personal projects, you can find me searching for geocaches or swimming laps at the pool.

EDUCATION

Carleton University:

Fourth Year student pursuing an undergraduate degree at Carleton University in Computer Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trilogy North America: August 2013 - November 2013

Contract Web Developer

Worked with small team developing a webapp for Trilogy North America:

- Created UI mockups and reviewed design decisions directly with client
- Developed webapp using Ruby on Rails web application framework
- Designed database schema to manage text and media to be used throughout site
- Developed front-end ERB HTML views
- Used jQuery for Ajax calls to the server

N-able Technologies: May 2013-August 2013

Junior Software Developer

Worked with UI team and project managers on migrating SDK app to N-Central UI:

- Developed JSP pages using Apache Struts 2, HTML, and Dojo
- Developed pages in UI using Java, JavaScript, Dojo, and XML
- Tested and debugged UI pages across multiple browsers
- Presented formal demos to team members, project managers, and product manager

N-able Technologies: May 2012-August 2012

Junior UI Developer

Worked with UI team on the N-Central software (RMM and MSP Service Automation Platform):

- Converted JavaScript codebase (using dojo version 1.6) to AMD format (dojo version 1.7+)
- Developed pages in the UI using Java, XML, and JavaScript
- Converted pages using Apache Struts 2 (previously developed in Struts 1)

N-able Technologies: May 2011-August 2011

Junior Software Developer

Worked in a team environment on various projects including:

- Bug fixes: User Interfaces and reports using C#, XML, ASP.NET, and SQL
- Worked with Quality Assurance team testing UI, reports, and other areas
- Converted legacy reports from SQL stored procedures to new data model
- Developed user manuals and tutorials

LANGUAGES, SKILLS, AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Software Development, Agile Methodologies, Android Development, iOS Development, Web Development, BlackBerry Development
- Java, Objective-C, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, XML, C++, C, C#, iOS Sprite Kit, Hibernate, Dojo, Struts, Git, MySQL, SQLite, Node.js, QML
- Eclipse, Xcode, Qt Creator, Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator
- Mac OS X, Linux, Ubuntu, Windows

AWARDS

Ontario Scholar, IBM Award, Communications Technology Award, Laptop Certificate, French Certificate

PERSONAL AND SCHOOL PROJECTS

RoamBot:

- Worked in a team of four and participated in Great Canadian Appathon 4
- Created a mobile game in 48 hours for iOS 7
- Used iOS Sprite Kit framework to create the game

Encore:

 Used REST architecture to create a social networking Android application for concerts and events

rAlarm (current project):

- Working on an Android application using the Rdio API
- An alarm clock that allows users to select tracks and playlists from their Rdio collection and profile

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Software Development, Geocaching, Film Photography, Swimming